一九六九年三月三日
美國海軍為飛行員成立了一間精英學校
目的是向飛行員傳授將失傳的空戰技巧
以確保在此畢業的一小部分飛行員
成為世上最一流的飛行員
他們成功了
現在海軍稱之為戰鬥機武器學校
飛行員則稱之為頂級飛行員部
【 壯 志 凌 雲 】
[印度洋，近期]
- 史葛，早 - 溫斯，早
- Morning, Scott. - Morning, Vince.
- 威斯，早 - 長官，早
- Morning, Wells. - Morning, sir.
鬼怪騎士，斯特拉克呼叫
Ghost Rider, this is Strike.
發現不明戰機，回程的戰機
We have unknown aircraft. Inbound, Mustang.
循0-9-0航線飛向敵機
Your vector, 0-9-0 for bogey.
上面的是誰？
Who's up there?
美洲豹、灰背隼 獨行俠和笨鵝
Cougar and Merlin and Maverick and Goose.
好極了，是獨行俠和笨鵝
Great. Maverick and Goose.
笨鵝，快回答
Talk to me, Goose.
收到，我發現他了 在左側二十度，三十英里外
Roger, I got him. Contact, 20 left at 30 miles.
以九百時速節飛近
Nine hundred knots closure.
美洲豹，你聽到了嗎？
Cougar, you hear that?
收到
Roger.
- 灰背隼，看到他了嗎？ - 收到，雷達探測到了
- Merlin, you got him? - Roger, I've got radar contact.
我要親眼確定他 美洲豹，你去引他上釣
I'll get a visual ID. Cougar, you hook him.
收到，我會將他煎皮拆骨
Roger, and I'll clean him and fry him.
母艦，我是鬼怪騎士 方位2-0-3
Mustang, Mustang, this is Ghost Rider, 2-0-3,
我控制住他了 他以2-7-0航線前進
I've got him inbound, bogey heading 2-7-0,
我們相距十英里，以九百節的速度靠近
We're at ten miles, 900 knots closure,
鬼怪騎士，向左十度，方位3-0
Ghost Rider, take Angels ten left, 3-0.
我們今天應該有訪客嗎？
Are we supposed to have visitors today?
沒有，長官
Negative, sir.
- 灰背隼，看看他是不是一個人 - 收到
- Merlin, see if he's a single. - Roger.
笨鵝，你發現有尾隨的嗎？
Goose, you see a trailer?
沒有，灰背隼
Negative, Merlin.
似乎只有他一個
Looks like he's a single.
美洲豹，我要和他正面交鋒
Cougar, I'm gonna go head-to-head with him.
獨行俠，別亂來，我不同意
Take it easy, Maverick. I don't like this shit.
我飛高一些 確定是不是只有他一個
I'm gonna break high and right, see if he's really alone.
獨行俠，我們以一千節的速度接近
We've got 1000 knots closure, Mav.
他朝著我們飛過來了
He's coming right at us.
兄弟，你在想什麼？
Okay, buddy, what's on your mind?
天啊，他們有兩個人
Holy shit, there's two of them.
是米格28，沒人試過這麼近
MiG-28s. No one's been this close before.
他們究竟在做什麼？ 什麼位置？
What the hell are they doing here? What's the position?
距離二百五十英里
Two hundred and fifty miles out, sir.
二百五十英里，叫他們馬上離開
Two hundred and fifty miles? Get them out.
美洲豹，你負責米格一號戰機 我去追米二號格戰機
Cougar, you've got MiG one. I'm going after MiG two.
他在陽光下不見了
I lost him in the sun.
該死，他在做什麼？ 灰背隼，你發現他了嗎？
Shit. What's he doing? You got him, Merlin?
他飛來飛去，他到我們後面了
He's coming around. He's coming around on our tail.
該死，我被他控制住了
Goddamn it. This bogey's all over me.
- 現在他們距離多遠？ - 二百英里，長官
- What's their range now? - Two hundred miles, sir.
如果小於一百五十英里 就出動五號戒備機
If they break 150 miles, launch the Alert Five aircraft.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
速度三百，獨行俠，消滅他
Air speed, 300. Go get him, Mav.
我準備進行導彈鎖定
I'm going for missile lock.
看看能不能把他嚇走
Let's see if we can scare this guy out of here.
來吧，鎖定他，親愛的，鎖定他
Come on, lock up, baby. Lock up, baby. Lock up.
已經鎖定他了，好極了
I got him locked. Bingo.
嚇倒他了，獨行俠 他夾著尾巴逃走了
We got him, Mav. He's bugging out and going home.
母艦，我是獨行俠 米格戰機二號走了
Mustang, this is Maverick. MiG two is headed home.
好吧，他們的位置在哪？
All right. What's their position?
距離一百八十英里，方位0-1-0
A hundred and eighty miles at bearing 0-1-0, sir.
他的導彈瞄準我們了 快點避開他
Cougar, he's got missile lock on us. Get away from this guy.
這是怎麼一回事？他追著我
What the hell is this shit? He's engaging me.
該死，母艦 這是鬼怪騎士，方位1-1-7
Goddamn it, Mustang. This is Ghost Rider, 1-1-7.
我被敵機控制住了
This bogey's all over me.
他用導彈鎖定我了，能允許我開火嗎？
He's got missile lock on me. Permission to fire?
未受攻擊前不能開火
Do not fire until fired upon.
笨鵝，他們就在我們下面
Goose, there they are, right below us.
米格戰機到最佳的開火位置上了 他在美洲豹後面
The MiG's in perfect firing position. He's right on Cougar's tail.
不對，笨鵝 他早就應該開火了
No way, Goose. He'd have fired by now.
他只是想激怒我們
He's just trying to piss us off.
獨行俠，快來幫我脫身
Maverick, get down here and get this asshole off me.
美洲豹，別緊張
Easy, Cougar.
帶他回來，協助我進入戰場
Bring it back, hard right. Help me engage.
我來了
I'm on my way.
我不能攻擊這個狗娘養的
I can't shoot this son of a bitch.
看看我們能不能跟他玩玩
Let's see if we can have a little fun with him.
你說的「玩玩」就是這樣？
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
你好啊
Greetings.
看這
Watch the birdie.
天啊，笑死我了
Jeez, I crack myself up.
這場景太精彩了，我應該當攝影師
This is a great shot, Mav. I should be a photographer.
美洲豹
Cougar...
你脫身了，米格戰機一號離開了
...your tail is clear. MiG one's bugged out.
美洲豹，我是獨行俠
Cougar, this is Maverick.
今天玩得真開心，是嗎？
We've had enough fun for one day, don't you think?
燃料不多了，我們回去吧
I'm getting a little low on fuel, so we're heading home.
在甲板上見
We'll see you on deck.
美洲豹，燃料不多，該走了
Cougar, we're running low on gas, we gotta get out of here.
美洲豹
Cougar.
快沒燃料了，美洲豹，快回去
We're on vapor, Cougar. Let's do it.
美洲豹，快啊
Cougar. Come on, Cougar.
快飛回艦上，美洲豹，快
Let's take it back to the ship, man, Come on, Cougar,
叫他盡快降落，他快沒燃料了
Get him on deck as soon as possible. He's gotta be low on fuel.
美洲豹，我們要降落了
Cougar, we gotta land this thing.
我們快沒燃料了，你明白嗎？
We are way low on gas. You understand me?
你沒事吧？
You all right, man?
獨行俠，還有四分三英里 降落時作出請示
Maverick, you're at three-quarters of a mile, call the ball,
收到，獨行俠請求降落
Roger. Maverick has the ball.
美洲豹，應該降落了，快點
Cougar, it is time to land, Let's do it,
笨鵝，美洲豹出事了
Goose, Cougar's in trouble.
別亂來，我們快沒燃料了 快點降落
Come on, Mav, we're getting low on gas. Let's land this sucker.
美洲豹
Cougar,
該死，獨行俠
Goddamn it, Maverick.
你在做什麼？ 我們不夠燃料這樣做
What are you doing, Mav? We've got no fuel for this.
我們要去幫美洲豹
We're going after Cougar.
叫他馬上降落，這是命令
You tell him to land that plane. That's an order.
鬼怪騎士，命令你降落
Ghost Rider, you are instructed to land,
馬上降落
Land immediately,
你們看到附近有航空母艦嗎？
Any of you boys seen an aircraft carrier around here?
我們有點小問題 那架米格戰機嚇壞他了
Mav, we got a little problem up here. That MiG really screwed him up.
他大概無法把戰機開回去
I don't think he can make it back.
美洲豹，不要緊，跟著我飛
You're okay, Cougar. Just stay on my wing,
我會帶你回去，跟著我
I'll take you all the way in. Just stay with me.
別緊張，好像逛公園一樣
Easy, Cougar. Just a walk in the park, buddy.
你飛得低了點，低了一點
You're a little low. You're a little low, Coug.
夥計，快點拉升
Come on, buddy, pull up.
快點拉升，美洲豹
Pull up, Cougar.
對了，快到了
That's it. Almost there.
你比跑道低了點，還有四分三英里
You're a little below glide path, three-quarters of a mile,
請求降落
Call the ball,
收到，准許降落
Roger, ball,
美洲豹，我們太低了
We're too low, Cougar. We're too low, Cougar.
加大動力
Increase power. Some more power!
請進
Come in.
長官
Sir.
美洲豹，你應該在醫護室 你在想什麼？
Cougar, you should be in sickbay. What's on your mind?
我的妻兒
My wife and kid, sir.
他今天幾乎變成孤兒 我還沒見過他
I almost orphaned him today, and I've never even seen him.
我不知道發生了什麼事 但是我很害怕
I don't know what happened up there, but I was so scared.
- 別這樣，我們以前也見過這種事 - 不，長官
- Come on, we've seen this before. - No, sir.
我的壓力太大了
I'm holding on too tight.
我已經受夠了，對不起，長官
I've lost the edge. I'm sorry, sir. I'm sorry.
美洲豹
Cougar.
謝謝，獨行俠
Thanks, Maverick.
獨行俠、笨鵝，進來
Maverick, Goose, come in here.
- 發生了什麼事？ - 我不知道
- What the hell's going on? - I don't know.
該死的
Shit.
獨行俠，你剛才做的事很勇敢
Maverick, you just did an incredibly brave thing.
可是你應該做的是降落
What you should have done was land your plane.
戰機不是你的，是納稅人的
You don't own that plane, the taxpayers do.
你真是狂妄自大
Son, your ego is writing checks your body can't cash.
你曾被降職 你三次失去當分隊長的資格
You've been busted. You lost your qualifications as section leader three times.
我兩次關你禁閉
Put in hack twice by me.
你曾高速飛過五個控制塔
With a history of high-speed passes over five air-control towers
和一個上將的女兒
and one admiral's daughter.
彭妮·本傑明？
Penny Benjamin?
- 你這笨蛋能在這兒真是走運 - 謝謝
- And you, asshole. You're lucky to be here. - Thank you, sir.
不說廢話了，獨行俠 你不是出自海軍名門
Let's not bullshit, Maverick, your family name ain't the best in the Navy.
你應該比其他人做得更好，你究竟在想什麼？
You need to be doing it better and cleaner than the other guy. Now, what is it with you?
我只想為國效力 當最好的海軍飛行員
Just wanna serve my country, be the best fighter pilot in Navy, sir.
獨行俠，別想騙我了
Don't screw around with me, Maverick.
你全憑直覺駕駛戰機，也許很出色
You're a hell of an instinctive pilot. Maybe too good.
我真想開除你，但是不行 我有了另一個麻煩
I'd like to bust your butt, but I can't. I got another problem here.
我要從隊中派人去米拉馬
I gotta send somebody from this squadron to Miramar.
我要做一些事 我難以置信的事
I gotta do something here. I still can't believe it.
我要讓你夢想成真 派你去面對一流的海軍
I gotta give you your dream shot. I'm gonna send you up against the best.
你們兩個會進高空利劍
You two characters are going to Top Gun.
你們會和世界上的頂級飛行員 交手五個星期
For five weeks, you're gonna fly against the best fighter pilots in the world.
本來你是第二，美洲豹是第一
You were number two, Cougar was number one.
美洲豹放棄了
Cougar lost it, turned in his wings.
你們就成了第一
You guys are number one.
但記著一件事： 你們這次要是搞砸了
But you remember one thing: You screw up just this much,
我會派你們開運輸機從香港運皮子
you'll be flying a cargo plane full of rubber dog shit out of Hong Kong.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
沒事了
That is all.
改天再向我匯報米格戰機的事
You can tell me about the MiG some other time.
兩位
Gentlemen.
- 祝你們好運 - 謝謝，長官
- Good luck, gentlemen. - Thank you, sir.
謝謝
Thank you.
[美國空軍基地，加州米拉馬]
海軍在韓戰的殺敵比率是十二比一
During Korea, the Navy kill ratio was 12-to-1.
我們一架戰機就能擊落敵人十二架
We shot down 12 of their jets for every one of ours.
到了越戰時比率降至三比一
During Vietnam, that ratio fell to 3-to-1.
我們的飛行員太依賴導彈了
Our pilots become dependent upon missiles.
他們失去了一些空戰技巧
They had lost some of their dogfighting skills.
組建高空利劍是為了教導你們空戰策略
Top Gun was created to teach ACM: Air Combat Maneuvering.
也就是空中格鬥
Dogfighting.
真令人興奮
This gives me a hard-on.
到了越戰末期 這一比率回升至十二比一
By the end of Vietnam, that ratio was back up to 12-to-1.
- 別跟我開玩笑 - 請拉開窗簾
- Don't tease me. - Blinds, please.
我想藉著這次機會 介紹指揮官給大家認識
I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce you to our commanding officer at Top Gun.
他是第一位獲得高空利劍飛行員獎的人
The very first man to win the Top Gun trophy.
你不會在其他地方找到比他更優秀的飛行員了
You will not find a finer fighter pilot anywhere in the world.
邁克·麥特卡福長官，代號毒蛇
Commander Mike Metcalf. Callsign: Viper.
各位
Gentlemen.
你們是海軍空戰人員中百里挑一的
You are the top one percent of all naval aviators.
是精英，精英中之精英
The elite. The best of the best.
我們會令你們更進一步
We'll make you better.
你們每天至少要執行兩項空戰任務
You'll fly at least two combat missions a day,
期間你們要上課 聽取對自己表現的評價
attend classes in between and evaluations of your performance.
你們在每次的空戰任務中 都要面對新挑戰
On each combat sequence, you're gonna meet a different challenge.
而每一次都會更加困難
Every encounter is gonna be much more difficult.
我們會教你們如何令F14戰機盡展所長
We're gonna teach you to fly the F-14 right to the edge of the envelope,
你們會比以前飛得更快
faster than you've ever flown before
也會更加危險
and more dangerous.
各位，我們不是在這兒制定政策
Now, we don't make policy here, gentlemen.
那是當選的政府官員所做的事
Elected officials, civilians do that.
我們只是這些政策的工具
We are the instruments of that policy.
雖然我們不是在打仗 但要時刻保持戰時狀態
And although we're not at war, we must always act as though we are at war.
你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
- 好鋼用在刀刃上 - 我只是在想誰是最一流的飛行員
- The tip of the spear best be sharp. - I'm just wondering who's the best.
你們可能會想誰是最一流的飛行員
In case some of you wonder who the best is,
他們的名字就在牆上
they're up here on this plaque on the wall.
最優秀的飛行員及其通訊員的名字 都會記錄在上面
The best driver and his RIO from each class has his name on it.
他們可以選擇回來當教官
And they have the option to come back here to be Top Gun instructors.
你認為你的名字會在上面？
You think your name's gonna be on that plaque?
是的，長官
Yes, sir.
你真是自以為是，周圍有這麼多人
That's pretty arrogant, considering the company you're in.
是的，長官
Yes, sir.
我喜歡飛行員自大
I like that in a pilot.
記著，離開這兒後 我們都是同一隊人
Just remember, when it's over out there, we're all on the same team.
各位，這兒是教大家如何戰鬥的
Gentlemen, this school is about combat.
當第二名是沒有意義的
There are no points for second place.
解散
Dismissed.
做得好
Nice going.
替補的勳章在女洗手間
The plaque for the alternates is down in the ladies' room.
天啊，真是笑死我了
Oh, Jesus. Oh, you kill me. You really do.
不...夥計們，「笨鵝」可是有兩個O的
No, no, no. There's two O's in "Goose", boys.
真是一個不愁沒目標的環境
This is what I call a target-rich environment.
你在兩條腿之間生活
You live your life between your legs, Mav.
笨鵝，你也可以來這兒的
Goose, even you could get laid in a place like this.
能找到朝我說髒話的女孩 我就高興了
I'm telling you, I'd be happy to find a girl who'd talk dirty to me.
獨行俠，你想知道誰是一流飛行員？
Mav, you wanted to know who the best is?
就是他，冰人
That's him. Iceman.
因為他開戰機時十分冷靜，從不犯錯
That's the way he flies, ice-cold, no mistakes.
磨滅你的耐性，令你沮喪 你一犯錯就會被他逮住
Just wears you down. You get bored, frustrated, do something stupid, and he's got you.
滑行者，你好
Hey, hey, Slider.
我還以為你想做飛行員呢 發生了什麼事？
Thought you wanted to be a pilot, man. What happened?
笨鵝，你真是個蠢才 你是靠誰進來的？
Goose, you're such a dickhead. Whose butt did you kiss to get in here?
名單很長，不過很有名
Well, the list is long but distinguished.
我的約翰遜也是
Well, so is my johnson.
你和冰人一組？
So you're flying with Iceman, huh?
- 你應該說冰人先生 - 母鵝，你好嗎？
- It's Mr. Iceman to you. - Hey, Mother Goose. How's it going?
很好，湯姆，這位是皮特·米切爾 湯姆·卡山斯基
Good, Tom. This is Pete Mitchell. Tom Kazansky.
- 恭喜你加入高空利劍 - 謝謝
- Congratulations on Top Gun. - Thank you.
美洲豹的事真令人遺憾
Sorry to hear about Cougar.
他和我在飛行學校時情同手足
He and I were like brothers in flight school.
- 他以前很棒的 - 他現在仍然很棒
- He was a good man. - Still is a good man.
我就是這個意思
Yeah, that's what I meant.
- 我也是這樣認為的 - 需要幫忙嗎？
- Thought so. - Say, you need any help?
幫忙什麼？
With what?
你想到了嗎？
You figured it out yet?
什麼？
What's that?
誰是最佳飛行員
Who's the best pilot.
不，我自己會想到的
No, I think I can figure that one out on my own.
聽說你喜歡單獨行事
I heard that about you. You like to work alone.
你一定是在幸運星之下行事
Mav, you must've soloed under a lucky star, huh?
我的意思是，先是米格戰機 然後又闖進了美洲豹的戰場
I mean, first the MiG, and then you guys slide into Cougar's spot.
我們不是闖進去 那也是我們的戰場
We didn't slide into Cougar's spot. It was ours, okay?
有些飛行員到退役時 還沒試過近距離接觸米格戰機
Some pilots wait their whole career just to see a MiG up close.
你們一定是既幸運又出名了
Guess you guys are lucky and famous, huh?
你想說的是臭名昭著吧
No, you mean notorious.
- 再見 - 一定會的
- I'll see you later. - You can count on it.
他們小時候一定被人虐待
They were abused children.
- 我們會有一段好時光 - 總是如此
- We're gonna have a good time. - Always.
這次應該輪到我了吧
Okay, I guess it's my turn, isn't it?
好吧，賭二十元
All right, the bet is $20.
- 二十元 - 對
- Twenty dollars. - Right.
你得對慾望有所認識才能在此刻勾搭上女人 就這麼說定了
You have to have carnal knowledge, of a lady this time, on the premises.
說定了
On the premises.
來吧，這只是一場賭博
Come on, Mav. A bet's a bet.
我不知道，只是... 只是這似乎對你不太公平
I don't know, it just-- It just doesn't seem fair. For you, I mean.
但是...她失去了愛的感覺
But... she's lost that loving feeling.
- 什麼？不，她還沒失去 - 她失去了
- She's lost--? No, she hasn't. - Yes, she has.
- 她還沒失去... - 笨鵝，她失去了
- She has not lost that-- - Goose, she's lost it.
獨行俠，你少來了
Mav-- Come on.
該死，我討厭她這樣
I hate it when she does that. Shit.
對不起，小姐
Excuse me, miss.
別擔心，我會幫你搞定的
Hey, hey, hey. Don't worry, I'll take care of this.
你不再閉上雙眼
You never close your eyes anymore
當我親吻你的雙唇
When I kiss your lips
你的指尖不再溫柔
There's no tenderness like before In your fingertips
你努力掩飾
You're trying hard not to show it
親愛的
Baby
可是，相信我，我知道的
But, baby, believe me, I know it
你已經失去了愛的感覺
You've lost that loving feeling That loving feeling
你失去了愛的感覺
You've lost that loving feeling
感覺一去不返
Now it's gone, gone, gone
坐下吧
Sit down.
謝謝
Thank you.
親愛的，我會為你下跪
Baby, baby, I get down on my knees for you
我喜歡這首歌，從沒見過這種搭訕
I love that song. I've never seen that approach.
你們兩個試過多少次？
How long have you two been doing this act?
- 我不知道，從… - 青春期開始？
- Oh, I don't know, since... - Puberty?
對
Right, puberty.
- 我叫夏洛特·布萊克伍德 - 我叫獨行俠
- I'm Charlotte Blackwood. - I'm Maverick.
獨行俠？你媽媽不喜歡你嗎？
Maverick? Did your mother not like you or something?
不，這是我的代號
No, it's my callsign.
- 你是飛行員 - 是的，我是海軍飛行員
- You're a pilot. - That's right, a naval aviator.
其實我們這樣做只幹過兩次
No, actually, we've only done this twice.
結果怎樣？
Oh, how'd you do?
第一次是一場大災難，死得很難看
Crashed and burned on the first one. It wasn't pretty.
- 第二次呢？ - 我不知道，明天告訴你
- The second? - I don't know. I'll tell you tomorrow.
但暫時來看還不錯
But it's looking good so far.
獨行俠
Well, Maverick,
我的朋友到了，和你聊得很愉快
my friend's just arrived, so it's been great talking to you.
- 彼利 - 你好
- Perry. - Hi.
你來了，我馬上過去
Hi. Here you go. I'll be with you in just a second, okay?
我可以問你一個私人問題嗎？
Listen, can I ask you a personal question?
那要看你問什麼
That depends.
你是個優秀飛行員嗎？
Are you a good pilot?
我認為我是
I can hold my own.
好極了
Great.
我不用擔心你要以唱歌來謀生了
Then I won't have to worry about you making your living as a singer.
我需要啤酒來滅火
I'm gonna need a beer to put these flames out. Yo!
好極了，真狡猾
Great, Mav. Real slick.
水手，你出海太久了嗎？
It was a long cruise, was it, sailor?
太久了
It was too long.
你想怎樣，就地進行嗎？
What did you wanna do, just drop right down on the tile and go for it?
不，其實我是想在這張桌子上
No, I actually had-- Had this counter in mind.
好極了，一定會很舒服
Great, that would be very, very comfortable. Yeah.
可能會
It could be.
其實我來 是希望你不會為那個老鬼做錯誤的決定
Actually, I came in here to save you from making a big mistake with that older guy.
真的？ 那我就能和你這種年輕人好了？
Really? So I could go on to a bigger one with a young guy like yourself?
可能吧
Maybe. No?
明天一早我便要工作
I've gotta be at work very early in the morning.
你在這兒做什麼？
Then what are you doing here?
你的朋友真厲害
Your friend was magnificent.
不
No.
你們也會受到獨立專家的訓練和評估
Now, you'll also be trained and evaluated by a few civilian specialists.
這兒有非軍事人員 是因為他們對敵機很有認識
The civilians are here because they are our very best source of information on enemy aircraft.
其中最有資格的 就是教官代表，代號狐貍
One of the most qualified is our TAGREP, callsign: Charlie.
她是天體物理學博士
She has a Ph.D. in astrophysics,
她也是一個非軍事人員 你們不用向她敬禮
and she's also a civilian contractor, so you do not salute her.
不過最好聽她的 因為軍方相信她對你們的評估
But you better listen to her, because the Pentagon listens to her about your proficiency.
- 交給你了，狐貍 - 謝謝
- It's all yours, Charlie. - Thank you.
大家好
Hello.
我們會用F5和A4模擬米格戰機
We will be dealing with F-5s and A-4s as our MiG simulators.
你們大多都應該知道
Now, then, as most of you know,
F5不具備米格28的推重比
the F-5 doesn't have the thrust-to-weight ratio the MiG-28 has.
更不會像米格28那樣 在低於三百節時放出能量
And it doesn't bleed energy below 300 knots, like the MiG-28.
不過米格28的反向飛行油箱確有問題
However, the MiG-28 does have a problem with its inverted flight tanks.
它不擅長做負重力飛行動作
It won't do a negative-G pushover.
最新的情報告訴我們它最多
The latest intelligence tells us that the most it will do
能夠連續做一個負...
is one negative--
對不起，上尉
Excuse me, lieutenant.
有什麼問題嗎？
Is there something wrong?
女士，米格戰機的資料不正確
Yes, ma'am, the data on the MiG is inaccurate.
哪兒不正確？
How's that, lieutenant?
- 我看過米格28做... - 是我們
- Well, I just happened to see a MiG-28 do-- - We, we.
對不起，笨鵝
Sorry, Goose.
我們見過米格28連續做四個負重力俯衝
We happened to see a MiG-28 do a four-G negative dive.
你在哪兒見到的？
Where did you see this?
- 這是機密資料 - 什麼？
- That's classified. - It's what?
是機密資料
It's classified.
我可以告訴你 但是之後就要殺了你
I could tell you, but I'd have to kill you.
上尉，我有權知道最高機密
Lieutenant, I have top-secret clearance.
五角大樓允許我比你知道得更多
The Pentagon sees to it that I know more than you.
那麼這次大概不同了
Well, ma'am, it doesn't seem so in this case, now, does it?
上尉...你當時在哪兒？
So, lieutenant... where exactly were you?
- 我們... - 謝謝
- Well, we... - Thank you.
當他穿越雲層時，我們在他後面 然後我飛到他上面
...started up on his 6 when he pulled through the clouds, and then I moved in above him.
你在他上面又怎會看到他？
Well, if you were directly above him, how could you see him?
- 因為我倒轉了 - 廢話
- Because I was inverted. - Bullshit.
不，他真是這樣做的，很精彩呢
No, he was, man. It was a really great move.
他倒轉了
He was inverted.
你倒轉著和米格28一起做四個負重力俯衝？
You were in a four-G inverted dive with a MiG-28?
是的
Yes, ma'am.
- 距離多遠？ - 大概兩米吧
- At what range? - About two meters.
實際上應該是一米半
It was actually about one and a half, I think.
是一米半 我拍下了當時的精彩景象
It was one and a half. I've got a great Polaroid of it.
他沒錯，一定是一米半
He's right there. It must be one and a half.
- 是張好照片 - 上尉
- It was a nice picture. - Lieutenant.
你當時在做什麼？
What were you doing there?
- 溝通 - 是溝通
- Communicating. - Communicating.
保持外交關係
Keeping up foreign relations.
我當時在向他喝倒彩
I was... You know, giving him the bird.
- 用手指表示 - 我明白，笨鵝
- You know, the finger. - Yes, I know the finger, Goose.
對不起，我討厭它這樣
I'm sorry, I hate it when it does that. I'm sorry.
對不起
Excuse me.
原來是你
So you're the one.
是的，女士
Yes, ma'am.
好吧，各位，我們要飛行了
All right, gentlemen, we have a hop to take.
這次飛行的規定高度在一萬英尺 無論如何不能低於這個高度
The hard deck on this hop will be 10000 feet. There'll be no engagement below that.
出發
Move it.
上尉
Lieutenant.
別再遲到，親愛的
Okay, well, don't be late again. You look great, honey.
謝謝，在預飛區見
Thanks, dear. See you in preflight.
上尉，你為什麼不告訴我 米格戰機是被你羞辱的？
Lieutenant, why didn't you tell me that you were the famous MiG insulter?
我說了會有分別嗎？
Would it have made any difference?
在女洗手間奡N不會
Not in the ladies' room, no.
那我們會怎樣呢？
What would've?
我是這兒的教官
I'm an instructor at this school.
每八個星期就會見到 二十個雄心勃勃的新丁
I see 20 new hotshots every eight weeks.
你一定能想像得到
Now, I'm sure you can figure that out.
上尉
Look, lieutenant.
我真的很想聽聽米格戰機的事
I'd just really like to hear about the MiG sometime.
你有權看最高機密 你可以自己看
You've got security clearance. You can read about it.
獨行俠
Maverick...
我很好奇
...I'm curious.
你戲弄米格戰機時 是誰在掩護美洲豹？
Who was covering Cougar while you were showboating with this MiG?
美洲豹表現很好
Cougar was doing just fine.
各位，這是你們在這的第一次飛行
Gentlemen, this is your first hop,
你們面對的戰機更小、更快 也更容易控制
The jets you are flying against are smaller, faster and more maneuverable,
就像米格戰機一樣
just like the enemy MiGs,
計時開始，我們將記錄你們的成績
The clock is ticking and as of now, we are keeping score,
他不見了，笨鵝
I lost him, Goose.
小子，讓我看看你有什麼能耐
Show me what you got, kid.
- 他不見了 - 我在找他了
- I lost him. - I'm looking, I'm looking.
看到了，他在我們後面，衝過來了
I got him, I got him. He's on our tail, coming hard.
我看到他了，行動
I got him. I got him. Here we go.
好吧，笨鵝，告訴我現在的情況
All right, talk to me, Goose.
他仍然在後面，在不斷接近我們 速度很快
He's still back there. He's closing in on us. He's closing fast.
小子，你可以逃，但是躲不掉
You can run, kid, but you can't hide.
來吧，傑斯特 看看我能不能逼你使出全力
Come on, Jester. Let's see if I can give you a run for your money here.
小心撞到山
Watch the mountains.
他仍然在後面
I still got him. He's still back there.
獨行俠，快點想辦法
Come on, Mav. Do some of that pilot shit.
我看到他了
Yeah, I got him.
來吧，快鎖定它
Come on, bring it right.
笨鵝，我受夠了
Goose, I've had about enough of this shit.
我要拉制動器，他就會飛過頭
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by.
你們死定了
Okay, you're mine.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
看看你現在的境況，傑斯特
Let's see what you've got now, Jester.
讓我們扭轉局勢吧
Okay, Mav, let's turn and burn.
他垂直飛，我也來
He's going vertical, so am I.
我們好像導彈一樣，咬住他
We're going ballistic, Mav. Go get him.
他要飛越規定高度了 快搶先一步，釘住他
He's going for the hard deck. Let's get down there first and nail him, Mav.
想都別想，傑斯特，你死定了
No way, Jester, you're mine.
我瞄準你了
I got you now.
傑斯特輸了
Jester's dead.
馬上拉升，飛離規定高度範圍，回基地
Get your butts above the hard deck and return to base immediately.
遵命
Yes, sir.
控制塔，鬼怪騎士請求低空飛越
Tower, this is Ghost Rider requesting a flyby.
鬼怪騎士，不行，航線繁忙
Negative, Ghost Rider, the pattern is full.
不，獨行俠，這不是個好主意
No. No, Mav. This is not a good idea.
對不起，笨鵝 是時候飛過控制塔了
Sorry, Goose, but it's time to buzz the tower.
臭小子
Goddamn son of a bitch.
真是精彩絕倫
Great balls of fire!
傑斯特輸了
Jester's dead.
- 你們贏了？胡說 - 不是大家都贏了嗎？
- You won? That's bullshit. - Didn't everybody?
贏了才怪，我們都慘敗而回
Hell, no, man, we got our butts kicked.
在三十秒內我們往這邊飛，他往那邊飛
Thirty seconds. We went like this, he went like that.
我問好萊塢他在哪兒 他竟然問我誰在哪兒？
I said to Hollywood, "Where'd he go?" Hollywood said, "Where'd who go?"
他就在對講機上取笑我們
Yeah, and he's laughing at us, right on the radio. He's laughing at us.
不，笑你們的是我，笨蛋
No, it's me laughing, dickhead.
- 我們贏了 - 好啊
- We won. - All right.
他們也贏了呢
They won too, man.
- 我沒聽說 - 是真的，我們打敗了傑斯特
- That's not what I heard. - No, we did, we got Jester.
不，低於規定高度的不算
No, no. Below the hard deck does not count.
規定高度？總之我們打敗了他
Hard deck, my ass. We nailed that son of a bitch.
- 你們真愛自吹自擂 - 卡山斯基，你有什麼問題嗎？
- You guys really are cowboys. - What's your problem, Kazansky?
你是大家的問題
You're everyone's problem.
因為有你，每次飛行都不安全
That's because every time you go up in the air, you're unsafe.
我不喜歡你，因為你很危險
I don't like you because you're dangerous.
對，冰人
That's right, Iceman.
我很危險
I am dangerous.
獨行俠，你和笨鵝馬上脫掉飛行衣
Maverick, you and Goose get your butts out of that flight gear
到毒蛇的辦公室
and up to Viper's office now.
記著，當第二名是沒分的
Remember, boys, no points for second place.
- 你們要比看起來聰明 - 閉嘴
- You're a lot brighter than you look. - You shut up, okay?
- 別在意，笨鵝 - 好吧
- Don't worry, Goose, don't worry. - Okay, I will.
這兩個自大狂 以四百多節的速度飛過控制塔
Two of your snot-nosed jockeys did a flyby on my tower at over 400 knots!
我要你們馬上找人負責，我受夠了
I want somebody's butt. I want it now. I've had it.
該死，第二次了
Goddamn it! That's twice.
一定要有人負責
I want some butts!
好吧，這也要算在賬上
Well, that'll just about cover the flybys.
跟我來
Follow me.
兩位，你們第一天過得真充實
Gentlemen. You had a hell of a first day.
這次任務的規定高度是一萬英尺
The hard deck for this hop was 10000 feet.
你們明知故犯
You knew it, you broke it.
希瑟利軍官看不見你們後 你們跟在他後面低飛
You followed Commander Heatherly below after he lost sight of you and called no joy.
為什麼？
Why?
長官，我看到了希瑟利軍官 他看到我飛到能開火的位置
Sir. I had Commander Heatherly in my sights. He saw me move in for the kill.
就飛越過規定高度
He then proceeded below the hard deck.
我們只有幾秒的時間低於一萬英尺
We weren't below 10000 for more than a few seconds.
我瞄準了他 見沒有危險就開火
I had the shot, there was no danger, so I took it.
你開了火，同時你破壞了重要守則
You took it. And broke a major rule of engagement.
飛越控制塔時又犯了另一條
Then you broke another one with that circus-stunt flyby.
米切爾上尉，守則是為了
Lieutenant Mitchell, Top Gun rules of engagement exist
你和你的隊員的安全而設定的
for your safety and for that of your team.
守則不可以隨時更改的，包括我在內
They are not flexible, nor am I.
不遵守的話就要被開除 清楚了嗎？
Either obey them or you're history. Is that clear?
是，長官
Yes, sir.
出去
Dismissed.
我真的很高興，謝謝你
I really enjoyed that, Mav, thanks a lot.
媽的
Holy shit.
我或者可以學習當貨車司機
Maybe I could learn how to be a truck driver.
你有貨車駕駛學校的電話號碼
Mav, you have the number of that truck-driving school
我們在電視上看到過
we saw on TV? Truck Master, I think it is.
我可能會需要它
I might need that.
評估報告顯示他桀驁不馴
His fitness report says it all. He's a wild card.
他靠直覺開戰機 完全無法預測
Flies by the seat of his pants. Completely unpredictable.
- 他嚇倒你了？ - 是的
- He got you, didn't he? - Yeah.
獨行俠，我曾經和他爸爸共事
Maverick. I flew with his old man.
告訴我 你想和他一起上戰場嗎？
Tell me one thing. If you had to go into battle, would you want him with you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我真的不知道
I just don't know.
- 還沒睡嗎？ - 是的
- You still awake? - Yeah.
有什麼事嗎？
What's up?
睡不著
Can't sleep.
當我知道可以進高空利劍時
You know, when I first realized that we were going to Top Gun,
我只想著拿飛行員獎
all I could think about was getting that trophy.
我要坦白跟你說
I gotta be straight with you, Mav.
現在，我只希望我們能畢業
Right now, I just hope we graduate.
我有家人 我不能浪費這個機會
I got a family to think about. I can't afford to blow this.
其實飛越控制塔不算什麼
Yeah, I guess that flyby wasn't such a big hit.
我知道你很難受
Look, man, I know it's tough for you.
他們因為你是杜克·米切爾的兒子 而不讓你進海軍學院
They wouldn't let you in the academy because you're Duke Mitchell's kid.
你要承受這個污名
You have to live with that reputation.
我們每次飛行時 你都像是在和鬼魂開戰一樣
But it's like every time we go up there, it's like you're flying against a ghost.
你令我緊張
It makes me nervous.
我只有你這個親人
You're the only family I've got.
我不會令你失望的，我保證
I'm not gonna let you down. I promise you.
回去吧
Get out of here.
在那種情形下 反向翻轉會很有效
A rolling reversal would work well in that situation.
如果我做十字形翻轉 就能馬上開火
If I reversed on a hard cross, I could immediately go to guns on them.
但在這種速度下，太快了
Yeah, but at that speed, it's too fast.
而且太過急進
It's a little bit too aggressive.
太過急進？
Too aggressive.
我覺得應該做的，就會去做
Yeah, I guess when I see something, I go right after it.
那晚，你沒告訴我你是誰
You didn't tell me who you were the other night.
你沒有給我機會說
You didn't give me a chance, did you?
是你的責任
You deserved it.
我知道 不過你是想要約我吃晚餐
I know. But you were tempted to ask me out for dinner.
- 不 - 不？
- No. - No?
不，我不和學員約會
No. I don't date students.
我看得出這對你很危險
I can see it's dangerous for you.
但是如果政府相信我，你也可以
But if the government trusts me, maybe you could.
這不只是像花式飛行那麼簡單
It takes a lot more than just fancy flying.
今晚五點半共進晚餐
一敗塗地，獨行俠？
Crash and burn, huh, Mav?
滑行者
Slider...
你很臭
...you stink.
開始
Let's go.
冰人，快打
Okay, Ice, hit it.
好樣的，繼續
That's good. Come on.
快，來吧
Let's go, now.
獨行俠，四比七，讓我們宰了他們 他們都是些畜生
Come on, Mav, 4-7. Let's get them. Those guys are animals.
來吧
Let's go.
好球，好球
Good serve, good serve.
那就對了
That's game.
好吧，我們要打敗他們
Okay. Fake block, stay down. We'll just take them.
來啊，你去那？ 想跑嗎？
Come on, where you guys going? You walking away?
我們贏了，我們贏了
We won, we won.
獨行俠，再打一局 就追成平手了
Mav. Mav. Come on, man. Just one more game. That evens it up.
- 來吧，我們能打敗他們 - 不行
- Come on, we can take them. - No.
- 來吧，我們能贏他們 - 我有事要辦
- No, we can, we got it. - I got some things I gotta take care of.
有事？就再打一局而已
Take care of? Just one more game.
- 求你了，就算是為了我 - 對不起
- Please? For me? - I'm sorry.
你是該內疚，來吧
You're sorry. Come on.
- 笨鵝媽媽，你的小姑娘呢？ - 就算是為了我
- Mother Goose, you pussy! - For me?
該死
Damn it.
上尉
Lieutenant?
不唱歌了嗎？
What, no singing?
- 我… - 不用道歉
- Look, I'm-- I'm-- - No apologies.
你不介意的話 我想去洗一個澡，很快
If you don't mind, I'm-- I'm gonna just take a quick shower
好讓你把這些弄完
while you're finishing up here.
可是我介意，我很餓
Yeah, I do mind. I'm hungry.
後來我想
And then I thought about it.
我想：
I thought:
「狐貍，你知道的，他是個聰明人
"You know, Charlie, he's a smart guy.
為什麼不乾脆告訴他 請他來的目的？」
Why don't you just tell him why you've got him here."
是什麼？
Well?
米格戰機
It's the MiG.
是米格戰機
The MiG.
只有你曾經面對過米格28
You're the only pilot who's been up against a MiG-28.
我正為升職而努力工作 如果成功的話
I'm trying for this big promotion at work, and if I get it,
我不會再留在這兒
I'm not gonna be here much longer.
你似乎什麼都想清楚了
It seems to me you've got it all figured out.
是
Yeah.
只是你忘記了酒
Except you did forget the wine.
對不起
Sorry.
你常常如願以償？
You always get what you want?
不…可能是吧
No, not always. Yeah, maybe.
那就別在意那架米格戰機
Then relax about the MiG.
這首歌…
This music.
你很熟悉嗎？
An old friend?
我父母很喜歡這首歌
My folks loved it.
我有很多年沒聽過了
I haven't heard this in years.
媽媽以前在她房
My mother used to call down from her room
總叫我一邊一邊的放它
and have me play this over and over again.
我很厭倦聽這首歌
I got so sick of it.
她卻沒有…
But not her, she....
她會獨坐在一旁 一聽就是幾個小時
Just sit up there alone, just listening, hours.
只是在那聽
Just listening.
他死後不久她也死了
She died shortly after him.
你爸爸怎樣死的？
What happened to your father?
你既然有權知道機密資料
I guess I kind of figured, with your security clearance,
應該比我知道得更多
you'd know more about him than I do.
我還沒知道得那麼深入
Well, I didn't get that far.
這是一個謎
Well, it's a big mystery.
他在1965年11月5日開著F4失蹤了
He disappeared in an F-4, November 5th, 1965.
聽說是他犯錯了
The stink of it was, he screwed up.
但是那不可能
No way.
我爸爸是很優秀的飛行員
My old man was a great fighter pilot.
但誰知道呢？ 一切都被列作機密資料
But who the hell knows? It's all classified.
一定有人知道的
Somebody must know.
有人什麼都知道
Yeah, somebody knows everything.
所以你總是只能拿到第二名？
Is that why you're always second best up there?
你真直接
You are direct, aren't you?
對不起，我遲到了
I'm sorry I was late.
對不起，我這麼直接
I'm sorry for being direct.
不用道歉
No apologies.
這會變得很複雜
This is gonna be complicated.
你去哪兒？
Where are you going?
我去洗個澡
I'm gonna take a shower.
謝謝，我在這很愉快
Thank you. I enjoyed being here.
你似乎需要再洗一個澡
It looks like you need another shower.
對
Right.
我想對你坦白
I'm gonna be honest with you.
你見過米格戰機 這會對我的工作大有幫助
Your MiG sighting is really important to my work, but...
但我不是常常請學員 到家中作客的
I don't normally invite students to my house.
你是…
You're...
希望你明白我有工作在身
But please understand, I still have a job to do.
- 早上好 - 長官
- Morning. - Sir.
我很高興我們這麼坦白
I'm glad we got that straight.
我告訴她這兒有多辛苦
I told her how tough it is here.
我累得跟死狗一樣
You know, my ass dragging like an old, tired dog.
我告訴她你在這兒 連一個女人也沒有
I told her that you didn't even have a woman here.
- 真的嗎？ - 知道她怎樣說嗎？
- Oh, really. - You know what she said?
他可能有八個呢
Said, "Well, he probably doesn't have one, he's got eight."
爸爸
Daddy.
獨行俠，笨鵝說你和教官墜入愛河了
So, Maverick, Goose tells me you're in love with one of your instructors.
- 是嗎？ - 我沒說過這件事
- Is that right? - I-- I didn't tell her that.
你有說過的
Yes, you did.
- 你有說過的 - 你竟然說出來
- Yes, you did. - I can't believe you said that.
- 那是秘密 - 不
- That was a secret. - No.
敵機處在很好的位置，請定格
The bogey has good position right here. All right, freeze-frame.
是抉擇的時刻了
Moment of choice.
F14處於防守態勢
The F-14 is defensive.
它有機會立即逃離
He has a chance to bug out right here.
最好先撤退以及保證戰機的安全
Better to retire and save your aircraft
這比處於劣勢要好
than push a bad position.
狐貍，你可以隨時補充
Charlie, jump in here anytime.
你在菱形區域內再多呆三秒
Now, you stay in that diamond another three seconds,
就會被敵機消滅
the bogey's gonna blow you out of the sky.
如果你選擇第五區向右突圍
You take a hard right, select zone five,
就能拖延時間逃走
you can extend an escape.
你作了一個很差的決定
You made a bad choice.
狐貍
Charlie.
一號戰機翻了一個S觔斗
Aircraft one performs a split S?
這是你最不該做的 米格戰機就在你後面
That's the last thing you should do. The MiG's right on your tail.
請定格
Freeze there, please.
你在米格戰機的射程範圍 你現在會想什麼？
The MiG has you in his gunsight. What were you thinking at this point?
你沒時間在空中思考了
You don't have time to think up there.
一想就死定了
If you think, you're dead.
用價值三千萬元的戰機打賭 賭得可真大呢
Well, that's a big gamble with a $30 million plane, lieutenant.
不幸地，他賭贏了
Unfortunately, the gamble worked.
米格戰機無法開火
The MiG never got a clean shot.
獨行俠做了一個激進的垂直飛行
Maverick makes an aggressive vertical move here,
到了頂部 他用導彈打敗了敵機
comes over the top, and he defeats the bandit with a missile shot.
這次的交手是一次勝利
The encounter was a victory,
不過這是不應該再做的
but I think that we've shown it as an example of what not to do.
下一個
Next.
從沒見過這麼大膽的舉動
Gutsiest move I ever saw, man.
接著的可以作為教科書的最佳案例
Now, then, this is a perfect example of a textbook maneuver.
上尉
Lieutenant.
獨行俠
Maverick.
上尉…
Lieutenant.
上尉
我對你的飛行評估 是我的專業意見
My review of your flight performance in the TACTS was right on, in my professional opinion.
我聽不到你說什麼
I can't hear you.
天啊，你以為我只會魯莽行事
Jesus Christ! And you think I'm reckless.
我飛行時就會讓你知道 我以我的隊員和戰機為先
When I fly, I'll have you know that my crew and my plane come first!
上尉，讓我把話說完
Well, I'm going to finish my sentence, lieutenant.
我對你的飛行評估是正確的
My review of your flight performance was right on.
- 是嗎？ - 是的
- Is that right? - That is right.
但是我有所保留
But I held something back.
我看得出你有飛行的天賦 但是我不能在那兒說出來
I see some real genius in your flying, Maverick, but I can't say that in there.
我害怕大家會看穿我
I was afraid that everyone in that TACTS trailer would see right through me.
我只是不想讓人知道 我愛上你了
And I just don't want anyone to know that I've fallen for you.
- 獨行俠 - 什麼事？
- Hey, Maverick. - Yeah.
聽說冰人的事了嗎？
You hear about Ice?
- 什麼事？ - 他又贏了
- What's that? - He won another one.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
我覺得需要
I feel the need,
- 需要加速 - 需要加速
- the need for speed. - The need for speed.
各位，這是第十九次飛行
Gentlemen, this is hop 19,
會有更多戰機和敵人
Multiple aircraft, multiple bogies,
訓練已經過了一半 最佳飛行員獎的爭奪仍然激烈
Your training is half over, The competition for the Top Gun trophy remains tight,
第一名是冰人
First place, Iceman,
第二名是獨行俠，只差兩分
Second place, Maverick, just two points behind,
他們來了
There they are.
在三英里外，十點鐘方向 大概還沒看見我們
Three miles, left, 10 o'clock. I don't think they see us yet.
好的，我看到他們了
Okay, I see them.
左邊有兩架A4，在十點鐘方向 繼續左轉
Two A-4s, left 10 o'clock level, continue left turn.
各位早上好，氣溫是110度
Good morning, gentlemen. The temperature's 110 degrees.
天啊，是毒蛇
Holy shit, it's Viper.
毒蛇在空中，好極了
Viper's up here, great.
該死
Oh, shit.
他可能也在說： 「該死的，是獨行俠和笨鵝」
Great. He's probably saying, "Holy shit, it's Maverick and Goose."
他一定在這樣說
Yeah, I'm sure he's saying that.
我盯住北面的敵機
I've got my eye on the northern bogey.
收到，我盯住南面的
Roger. I got the southern guy.
好萊塢，你先走，我掩護你
Hollywood, you've got the lead, I'll cover you.
傑斯特，現在分開走
Break now, Jester.
好萊塢，毒蛇不見了 先對付傑斯特吧
Hollywood, we're losing Viper. Let's just stay on Jester.
收到，我去對付他
Roger, I'm on him.
笨鵝，把毒蛇找出來 他一定在附近
Goose, find Viper. He's out there somewhere.
和好萊塢一起，我們要掩護他
Stay with Hollywood, Mav, we're covering his wing.
笨鵝，是毒蛇，他在三點鐘方向
Goose, there's Viper. 3 o'clock, low.
和好萊塢一起，我們在掩護他
Stay with Hollywood, Mav. We're his cover.
獨行俠，別離開我
Don't you leave me, Maverick.
好萊塢，你看起來很好
Hollywood, you're looking good.
我去對付毒蛇
I'm going after Viper.
獨行俠，去你的
Goddamn you, Maverick.
獨行俠，別離開他
Mav, don't leave him.
笨鵝，好萊塢沒事的 我想打敗毒蛇
Goose, Hollywood's okay. I want Viper.
準備，毒蛇過來了
Stand by. Viper's coming down.
該死，我們面對面了 我們竟然這樣做
Holy shit, we're head-to-head. I can't believe we're doing this.
搖滾一下吧 機不可失，笨鵝
Rocking roll. Here's our chance. It's a big one, Goose.
來吧，該死的
Come on, goddamn it.
來啊，獨行俠，跟著來啊
Come on, Mav, keep coming.
選定響尾蛇導彈
Okay. Sidewinder missile selected.
來吧，親愛的
Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
回來啊，對了
Come around, come around. That's it, that's it.
天啊，他真厲害
Jesus, this guy's good.
笨鵝，他要去哪兒？
Goose, where's he going?
來啊，繼續跟著我啊
Come on, come on, come on, keep coming. Keep coming.
來吧，親愛的
Come on, baby.
該死，這小子真厲害
Damn, this kid's good.
他太接近，不能用導彈 改為用機槍
He's too close for missiles, Goose, I'm switching to guns.
快來啊，來啊
Come on, come on, come on.
堅持住，堅持住
Stick with me, stick with me.
等一下，笨鵝，看看後面
What--? Hold it. Goose, check our tail.
該死，是傑斯特
Shit. There's Jester.
成功了，獨行俠輸了 小子，你玩完了
Bingo, Maverick's dead. You're out of there, kid.
該死
Shit.
國防部很遺憾要告訴你
The Defense Department regrets to inform you
你的兒子因為太笨而戰死沙場
that your sons are dead because they were stupid.
真刺激
Great balls of fire.
算了吧，大家回去 由毒蛇帶頭
Okay, knock it off, gentlemen. Let's go home. Viper has the lead.
還有三十秒，狼人，我要進來了
Thirty seconds, Wolfman, and I'm coming in.
- 閉嘴！ - 天哪，該死的
- Shut up! - God, buttnose.
我從沒見過這麼精彩的空戰
That was some of the best flying I've seen yet,
直至你們被打敗為止
right up the part where you got killed.
你永遠不該離開僚機
You never, never leave your wingman.
獨行俠
Maverick...
問題不在你的飛行技術 而是你的態度
...it's not your flying, it's your attitude.
敵人很危險 但是你比敵人更加危險
The enemy's dangerous, but right now you're worse than the enemy.
你既危險又愚蠢
You're dangerous and foolish.
你未必喜歡你的隊友
You may not like the guys flying with you,
他們也未必喜歡你 但是你究竟是哪一方？
they may not like you, but whose side are you on?
起碼毒蛇在打敗我們之前 打敗了冰人
Well, at least Viper got Iceman before he got us.
我們仍然有機會得獎
We still got a shot at it.
那是愚蠢的行為，我是知道的
That was stupid. I know better than that.
不會再發生這種事了
It'll never happen again.
我知道
I know.
我知道的
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
Thinking about your love Drives a man insane
You break my will Oh, what a thrill
Goodness gracious Great balls of fire
獨行俠，快去制止他吧 他沒使你難為情嗎？
Maverick, would you go fetch him? Doesn't he ever embarrass you?
笨鵝，當然沒有 不過，有時候…
Goose? Hell, no. Well, there was the time...
- 上將的女兒 - 什麼？
- Admiral's daughter. - What?!
承認吧
Come on.
他把你飛過彭妮·本傑明的事告訴我了
He told me all about the time you went ballistic with Penny Benjamin.
是嗎？好極了
Did he? Well, that's great.
他把一切都告訴我了
He tells me about all of them, Maverick.
我的小天使笨鵝 早早回家準備去教堂
How my little angel Goose goes home early for church,
你就常常帶火辣辣的女人回家
and you, you always go home with the hot women.
好吧，謝謝你，嘉露
All right, thank you, Carole.
我去和笨鵝一起難為情
I'm gonna go embarrass myself with Goose for a while.
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
Thinking about your love Drives a man insane
You broke my will Oh, what a thrill
Goodness gracious Great balls of fire
我想警告你，獨行俠很危險
I would love to be able to warn you off about Maverick,
可是我很喜歡他
but I just love him to death.
我認識皮特很多年了
You know, I've known Pete for a lot of years now,
有一件事我可以肯定的告訴你
and I'm telling you, one thing's for certain.
今晚世界上會有很多人心碎
There are hearts breaking wide open all over the world tonight.
- 為什麼？ - 因為…除非你是個笨蛋
- Why? - Because unless you are a fool,
他已經不再在情場上鬼混了
that boy is off the market.
他是百分百、史無前例地愛上了你
He is 100 percent, prime-time in love with you.
笨鵝，臭男人
Hey, Goose, you big stud!
我的確是，親愛的
That's me, honey.
- 和我上床，否則你會永遠失去我 - 告訴我怎樣回家，親愛的
- Take me to bed or lose me forever. - Show me the way home, honey.
乖兒子，和大家一起唱
Come on, brother, sing with the family.
You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain
Thinking about your love Drives a man insane
You broke my will Oh, what a thrill
Goodness gracious Great balls of fire
獨行俠
Maverick...
臭男人，和我上床 否則你會永遠失去我
...you big stud, take me to bed or lose me forever.
各位，這是第三十一次飛行 你們還有兩星期就畢業了
Okay, gentlemen, this is hop 31, Two weeks to graduation,
最佳飛行員獎的歸屬仍有懸念 每一分都很重要
Top Gun trophy is still up for grabs, so every point counts,
還剩九次飛行了，分數咬得很緊 是時候來一次全勝了
Well, it's bottom of the ninth, the score is tied. It's time for the big one.
獨行俠，你這次能贏嗎？
You up for this one, Maverick?
這跟在公園散步一樣容易
Just a walk in the park, Kazansky.
呼叫，有多架敵機，方位1-6-5
Contact. Multiple bogies, 1-6-5.
距離兩英里 他們似乎想遠離我們
Two miles. Looks like they're going away from us.
不，我看到他們了，在兩點鐘方向 我來了
Ho, I see them, tallyho, right 2 o'clock. I'm in.
我也加入
I'm in.
這個臭小子截住我了
That son of a bitch cut me off.
快，天啊 冰人，快開火
Come on, come on. Jesus Christ. Ice, take the shot.
冰人，快點讓開
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there.
我的角度不好 太近了，不能用導彈
I can't get the angle. I'm too close for missiles.
現在改為用機槍
I'm switching to guns.
冰人，你不開火就走開
Ice, fire or clear.
天啊，我在這兒也能開火
Look at this! Jesus Christ, I can take a shot right here!
我只需要多二十秒
I need another 20 seconds, then I've got it.
我來了，我已經鎖定了
I'm moving in. I've got the shot.
獨行俠，我們上，快
Come on, Mav, let's get in there! Come on, Mav!
獨行俠不耐煩了 冰人，快開火
Maverick's getting impatient. Come on, take the shot.
再多十秒就行了
Ten more seconds, then I've got him.
冰人，快走開 獨行俠，出手吧
Come on, Ice, get the hell out of there! Let's do it, Mav.
冰人，從右邊走開，我要上來
Ice, come off high right. I'm in.
- 再多五秒 - 去右邊，冰人，我來了
- Five more seconds. - Come off high right, Ice. I'm in.
我走開，該死
I'm off. Shit!
- 我們在噴氣流之中 - 該死
- We're in his jet wash! - Holy shit!
情況不妙，該死 引擎停了，獨行俠
This is not good. Shit, we got a flameout, Mav.
引擎一號停了
Engine one is out.
引擎二號也停了
Engine two is out!
笨鵝，我無法控制戰機
Goose, I'm losing control. I'm losing control.
失去控制了，無法回復正常
I can't control it. It won't recover.
該死
Shit.
禍不單行，我們無法控制戰機
It's coupling up, Mav! We're out of control.
情況不妙
This is not good! This is not good!
請求救援，獨行俠出事了 機身在不停打轉
Mayday, mayday. Mav's in trouble. He's in a flat spin.
快掉進節了
He's heading out to sea.
高度八千，七千
Altitude 8000, 7000.
現在只有六千
Six. We're at six, Mav.
我被拋到前面，笨鵝 我摸不到跳機桿
I'm pinned forward, Goose. I can't reach the ejection handle.
笨鵝，你把我們彈出去
Goose, you're gonna have to punch us out.
我摸不到跳機桿，快點
I can't reach the ejection handle. Eject.
- 我在盡力了 - 快
- I'm trying! I'm trying! - Eject! Eject!
快，小心機艙蓋
Eject! Watch the canopy!
笨鵝，不
Goose! Goose! Oh, no!
天啊
Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God.
請你放手，你要放開他
Sir, let go of him. You gotta let him go, sir.
你怎樣？
How you doing?
我沒事
I'm all right.
笨鵝死了
Goose is dead.
我知道
I know.
開戰機開得久了 總會遇到這種事
You fly jets long enough, something like this happens.
他是我的通訊員 這是我的責任
He was my RIO, my responsibility.
我在越戰的部隊 十八架戰機有八架墜毀，總共十條人命
In my squadron in Vietnam, we lost eight of 18 aircraft. Ten men.
第一個人死了，你也會死
First one dies, you die too.
但還有人活著，你可以指望他們
But there will be others. You can count on it.
放下吧
You gotta let him go.
這可能是我的錯
I think maybe it was my fault.
我不知道是哪兒出錯
I don't know what the hell went wrong.
我想幫你，我知道你很難接受
I'd like to help. I know it's difficult.
天啊，我希望他能活過來
God, I want him back.
你需要我的話隨時找我
I'll be here if you need me, okay?
天啊，他很喜歡和你並肩作戰
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick.
就算沒遇上你，他也會當飛行員
But he'd have flown anyway without you.
雖然他討厭這種事 但他還是會做
He'd have hated it, but he would've done it.
我們發現這架F14的右側引擎 捲進了破壞性的氣流
We find that the F-14 flat spin was induced by the disruption of airflow into the starboard engine.
這種破壞令引擎停轉 出現過多的偏航率
This disruption stalled the engine, which produced enough yaw rate
結果令機身不停打轉 無法修正
to induce a spin which was unrecoverable.
氣流導致引擎停轉 不是米切爾上尉可避免的
There was no way Lieutenant Mitchell could either see or avoid the jet wash which produced the engine stall.
所以資詢會認為皮特·米切爾上尉
Therefore, the board of inquiry finds that Lieutenant Pete Mitchell
並沒在7月29日的事故中犯錯
was not at fault in the accident of 29 July.
這次意外 不會記錄在米切爾上尉的檔案中
Lieutenant Mitchell's record will be cleared of this incident.
米切爾上尉馬上復職
Lieutenant Mitchell is restored to flight status without further delay.
調查完畢
These proceedings are closed.
盡快讓他恢復飛行
Get him up flying, soon.
小子，快點進入戰場
Come on, kid, come on. Get in there. Engage.
獨行俠，兩點鐘方向有一架敵機
All right, you got a bogey at 2 o'clock low, Maverick.
你的位置很好 簡直是輕而易舉
You got the angle. Piece of cake, pal.
快開火，小子
Take the shot, kid. Take the shot.
獨行俠，你隨時都可以開火
You can engage any time, Maverick.
你要去哪兒？
Hey, where the hell are you going?
情況不妙
It's not good. It doesn't look good.
情況不妙是什麼意思？ 情況好到不得了
What do you mean, it doesn't look good? It doesn't get to look any better than that.
你本來可以擊中他的 我們可以擊中他的
Hey, man, we could've had him. Hey, we could've had him, man!
我準備好時自然會開火
I will fire when I am goddamn good and ready!
你明白了嗎？
You got that?!
他仍然未恢復過來 他不願戰鬥
He can't get back in the saddle. Won't engage.
只過了幾天
It's only been a few days.
他可能無法恢復過來了
You know, he just might not make it back.
多讓他飛幾次
Keep sending him up.
米切爾
Mitchell...
笨鵝死了我很難過
...I'm sorry about Goose.
大家都喜歡他
Everybody liked him.
我很難過
I'm sorry.
你好，我是狼人
Hi, it's Wolfman.
獨行俠剛剛退學了
Yeah, Maverick just quit.
對不起
Excuse me.
我可以坐下嗎？
May I?
隨便
Please.
和他要的一樣
I'll have what he's having.
是毒藥吧
Hemlock, is it?
是冰水
Ice water.
你不和我道別嗎？
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
聽說你得到華盛頓的工作了，恭喜
I heard you got that job in Washington. Congratulations.
謝謝
Thanks.
但是我不會不辭而別
But I wasn't gonna leave without saying goodbye.
看到你真好
It's good to see you.
謝謝
Thanks.
你要去哪兒？
Where you going?
你連機票也沒有吧
You don't even have a ticket, do you?
我看過所有證據 這不是你的責任
Listen, I've seen all the evidence, and it's not your responsibility.
不是你的錯 你是海軍堛犖諨^
It's not your fault. You're one of the best pilots in the Navy.
你在高空戰鬥是很危險
What you do up there, it's dangerous.
但是你得繼續下去
But you've got to go on.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我剛認識你時 你的生活很充實
When I first met you, you were larger than life.
看看你
Look at you.
你不過快節奏生活 是不會快樂的
You're not gonna be happy unless you're going Mach 2 with your hair on fire,
- 你知道的 - 不，完了
- you know that. - No, it's over.
- 已經完了 - 作為精英中的精英
- It's just over. - To be the best of the best
就是要犯錯後仍然繼續努力 這對大家來說都一樣
means you make mistakes and then you go on. It's just like the rest of us.
你以為我不知道嗎？
You don't think I know that?
我是來幫你的
I'm here to help.
謝謝你
Look, thank you.
我需要別人幫我的話 自然會開口
But if I wanted help, really, I would have asked for it.
原來我來遲了
So I'm too late.
你已經決定離開了
You've already left.
你什麼都沒學到
You didn't learn a damn thing, did you?
你只學會退縮
Except to quit.
你真的很擅長做這種事呢
You've got that maneuver down real well.
再見了，皮特·米切爾
So long, Pete Mitchell.
你好，獨行俠，請進
Well, hi, Maverick, come on in.
- 你好嗎？ - 我很好
- How are you doing? - Good.
- 真的，你真的沒事？ - 我很好
- Really? You sure you're feeling okay? - Oh, I feel great.
珍美，過來 你要喝點什麼嗎？
Jamie, come on. Can I get you a drink or anything else like that?
- 不必了，謝謝 - 那好吧，請隨便坐
- No, thank you. - Okay, well, why don't you just make yourself comfortable.
邁克馬上就下來了
Mike will be right down.
謝謝
Great, thank you.
你爸爸和我在奧利士卡尼號的 VF-51小隊並肩作戰
I flew with your old man. VF-51, the Oriskany.
你真的很像他
You're a lot like he was.
或多或少
Only better and worse.
他是一個天生的英雄主義者
He was a natural heroic son of a bitch, that one.
他真的沒做錯
So he did do it right.
是的，他沒做錯
Yeah, he did it right.
所以你這樣開戰機？ 你想證明什麼？
Is that why you fly the way you do? Trying to prove something?
你爸爸的確沒做錯
Yeah, your old man did it right.
我要告訴你的事是機密 可能會令我丟掉工作
What I'm about to tell you is classified. It could end my career.
我們置身於一場噩夢般的空戰之中
We were in the worst dogfight I ever dreamed of.
敵機像螢火蟲般佈滿天空
Bogies like fireflies all over the sky.
他的F4戰機被擊中，他受了傷 他本來可以回基地
His F-4 was hit, he was wounded, but he could've made it back.
但是他留在戰場 在墜毀之前救了三架戰機
He stayed in it, saved three planes before he bought it.
我怎麼會從沒聽說過？
How come I never heard that before?
州政府不會告訴家屬
That's not something the State Department tells dependents
因為地圖出錯而發生戰事
when the battle occurred over the wrong line on some map.
- 你當時在場？ - 是
- So you were there? - I was there.
你在想什麼？
What's on your mind?
我的選擇
My options, sir.
很簡單
Simple.
你已經拿到足夠分數
First, you've acquired enough points to show up tomorrow
出席明天的畢業禮
and graduate with your Top Gun class.
或者退學
Or you can quit.
這不是丟臉的事 那樣打轉我也會被嚇倒
There'd be no disgrace. That spin was hell. It would've shook me up.
你認為我應該退學？
So you think I should quit?
我沒說過
I didn't say that.
你覺得是你害了笨鵝 你對自己沒信心
The simple fact is, you feel responsible for Goose, and you have a confidence problem.
我不會坐在這兒跟你說好話
Now, I'm not gonna sit here and blow sunshine up your ass, lieutenant.
一個好飛行員必須評估發生的事
A good pilot is compelled to always evaluate what's happened.
這樣才能學以致用
So he can apply what he's learned.
到了高空我們就要全力以赴 這是我們的職責
Up there, we gotta push it. That's our job.
上尉，這全看你的選擇
It's your option, lieutenant, all yours.
對不起，在週日打擾你 謝謝你抽空見我
Sorry to bother you on a Sunday, sir, but thank you very much for your time.
不要緊，祝你好運
No problem. Good luck.
房子出租
- 各位 - 獨行俠在哪兒？
- Gentlemen... - Where's Maverick?
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
你知道他有什麼打算嗎？
You know what he's planning to do?
他一定很難過
Gotta be hard on the guy, though.
恭喜
Congratulations.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 恭喜 - 謝謝
- Congratulations. - Thanks, Mav.
長官
Sir.
各位
Gentlemen.
我討厭要在派對 失去控制前把它結束
I hate to break up the party before it really gets out of hand,
但是我們有事要做
but there is work to be done.
你們有一些人要馬上離開
Some of you have to depart immediately.
我們遇上了危機
We have a crisis situation.
- 冰人、滑行者 - 有
- Ice, Slider. - Yo.
- 好萊塢、狼人 - 是
- Hollywood, Wolfman. - Yes, sir.
- 獨行俠 - 長官
- Maverick. - Sir.
獨行俠，你到航空母艦 就會有通訊員
Maverick, you'll get your RIO when you get to the ship.
找不到的話
And if you don't...
通知我，我和你一起飛
...give me a call. I'll fly with you.
是
Sir.
[24小時後，印度洋]
各位，這是敏感事件
Gentlemen, this is bull's-eye.
通訊船SS賴頓號失去控制 漂移進了外國海域
The communication ship SS Layton has become disabled and has wandered into foreign territory.
一小時內會開始營救行動
A rescue operation is to begin within the hour.
你們的任務 就是空中支援營救行動
Your mission is to give air support to that rescue.
該區有米格戰機，形勢十分緊張
There are MiGs in the area, and tensions are high.
受到襲擊可以還擊
If you witness a hostile act, you will return fire.
米格戰機有飛魚反艦導彈
Those MiGs carry the Exocet anti-ship missile.
他們可在一百英里以外發射導彈
They can fire that missile from 100 miles away.
各位，這是真正的戰鬥 這是你們受訓的目的
Gentlemen, this is the real thing. This is what you've been trained for.
你們是美國的精英 讓我們感到光榮吧
You are America's best. Make us proud.
- 冰人 - 是 長官
- Ice. - Yes, sir.
- 好萊塢 - 是 長官
- Hollywood. - Yes, sir.
第二組，獨行俠，你和灰背隼做後援
Sector two. And Maverick, you back them up with Merlin on Ready Five.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
起立
Rise!
- 對不起，長官 - 什麼事？
- Excuse me, sir. - Yes.
我不針對人 但是就獨行俠來說
This is not personal, but with regard to Maverick,
他是最好的後援嗎…
is he the best backup--?
我知道你在想什麼 總之你照著辦吧
I know what's on your mind, Kazansky, just get on it.
母艦，發現敵機通知我？
Mustang, can you give me a mode-four check?
伏都一號，有兩架敵機在十二點鐘方向 距離十五英里
Voodoo one, you've got a pair of bogies, 12 o'clock, 15 miles.
伏都一號，方位0-9-0 雷達顯示在十五英里
Voodoo one, Voodoo one, 0-9-0, radar contact 15 miles.
他們的時速是五百節
They're doing 500 knots.
收到，那就是敵機
Roger, that's your bogey.
他們在正前方十五英里 速度六百節
Got them dead ahead, 15 miles, air speed is 600 knots.
敵機速度六百五十節 我們靠得太近，離遠點
Bogies' air speed, 650, We're a little close together, Let's take a wider split,
他們在一萬五千英尺高空 正前方十英里
They're at 15000 feet now, dead ahead, ten miles,
正在加速
Air speed is still increasing,
八百節，正前方八英里
Eight hundred knots. Dead ahead, now, eight miles. Dead ahead, now, eight miles.
- 好萊塢，看到他們了嗎？ - 還沒看到
- Wood, you got them? - Not yet, I can't see them.
一定是在接近，我很興奮
They must be close, I'm getting a hard-on.
好萊塢，我先走一步 確定他們的位置
Okay, Wood, I'm taking the lead. Let's identify them.
收到，冰人 你先走，我在你左下方
Roger, Ice, you got the lead. I'm on your left side, a little low.
獨行俠已經準備好出動
Maverick's up and ready in Alert Five.
好極了
Good, good.
好萊塢，敵機仍被鎖定 他在你左邊
Hollywood, my bogey's still locked up, He's drifting to the left,
仍以0-9-0航線飛行
Still maneuvering course 0-9-0,
好萊塢，飛向右邊會有較好的角度
Okay, Wood, let's bring it to the right, and we'll get a better angle on them,
冰人，我們有麻煩
Ice, we got a problem here.
我在雷達上發現了四架戰機
Now I'm breaking out four aircraft on the radar.
不是兩架，是四架敵機
Not one pair, two pair. Repeat, four bogies.
好萊塢，有四架敵機
Wood, we've got four bogies.
- 弄錯了，是五架 - 是五架，長官
- Wrong! Make that five! - There's five, sir.
- 五架？ - 是的，長官
- That's five? - Yes, sir.
該死
Oh, shit!
他用雷達鎖定了我們
He's got a radar lock on us!
好萊塢，快離開 快避開，去你的
Get out of there, Hollywood! Get out of there, goddamn it!
- 左轉 - 被擊中了
- Break left! - I'm hit! I'm hit!
我們被炸爛了，我無法控制戰機
We're coming apart! I can't control it! Hold on!
- 我們在下落 - 好萊塢被擊中
- We're going down! - Wood's been hit! Wood's been hit!
該死，好萊塢被擊中
Shit! Wood's been hit!
伏都一號，好萊塢被擊中
Voodoo one! Wood's been hit! Wood's been hit!
好萊塢被擊落了
We've lost Hollywood! Repeat, we've lost Hollywood!
- 我們失去了僚機 - 叫獨行俠出動
- We've lost our wingman, - Launch Maverick on Alert Five.
找出好萊塢和狼人的位置 出動救援直升機
Get a bearing on Hollywood and Wolfman and launch the rescue helicopter immediately,
- 獨行俠起飛了 - 冰人，你在哪兒？
- Maverick's airborne. - Iceman, what's your position?
方位0-9-0，180英里以外
0-9-0 at 180 miles.
從左邊來了
We're coming in left!
有三架米格戰機在正前方 從左側向下飛
Three MiGs, dead ahead, coming down the left side.
我去對付他們 令他們飛到左邊
I'm going after them. I'm bringing it around to the left.
我們後面有四架敵機 總共是六架
We got four on our tail! That makes six of them!
你認為誰會在射擊範圍之內？
Who do you think is hooking in the guns range?
他開火了，右轉
He's firing! Break right!
我是伏都一號，我們只能防守
Mustang, this is Voodoo one, we are totally defensive.
- 快出動戒備戰機 - 他們在哪兒？
- Launch the alert fighters, - Where are they?
從160英里以外高速飛來
A hundred and sixty miles and closing in fast, sir.
叫韋勒和森堅準備
Ready Willard and Simkin off CATs three and four.
獨行俠以超音速趕來 三十秒內趕到
Maverick's supersonic. I'll be there in 30 seconds.
快過來，我們面對五架敵機
Move your ass! Get up here! I'm engaged with five. Repeat, five.
我身處險境
I'm in deep shit!
韋勒和森堅怎樣了？
What about Willard and Simkin?
兩部發射器都壞了 不能再發射戰機
Both catapults are broken. We can't launch any aircraft yet, sir.
- 要多久才能修好 - 十分鐘
- How long? - It'll take ten minutes.
十分鐘？兩分鐘內就玩完了 快想辦法
Bullshit, ten minutes. This thing will be over in two minutes. Get on it!
一架米格戰機在十二點鐘方向
One MiG, 12 o'clock high! One MiG, 12 o'clock high!
小心後面
Watch your back! Watch your back!
右轉
Break right!
該死，就差一點
Shit, that was close!
獨行俠，快來幫忙
Maverick, how about some help here?
- 你在哪？ - 小子，快過去
- Where the hell are you? - Come on, kid, hang in there.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
獨行俠，快援手 快進入戰場，該死
Maverick, how about some help? Engage, goddamn it!
獨行俠，後面有一架米格戰機
Maverick, we got a MiG on our tail.
小心
Watch out! Watch out!
該死，我們剛剛飛過噴氣流
Shit, we just flew right through his jet wash.
快點控制機身
Get control, Mav! Get control!
我們修正了，現在進入戰場吧
Good recovery, Mav. Okay, let's get in there.
我們要幫助冰人
Come on, we gotta help Ice.
快點回到戰場，獨行俠
Come on, let's get back in the game, Maverick!
- 快去 - 我辦不到
- Come on! - No. It's no good.
- 快去，獨行俠 - 不行
- Get in there, Maverick! - It's no good.
去你的，獨行俠竟然退縮
Goddamn it! Maverick's disengaging!
我早就知道會這樣，該死
I knew it! Shit!
去你的，獨行俠
Goddamn it, Maverick!
回去，獨行俠 你不能離他而去
Get in there, Maverick! You can't leave him! Come on! Maverick!
- 你在做什麼？ - 笨鵝，和我說說話
- What the hell are you doing? - Talk to me, Goose.
快回去，為了上帝
Get in there, for chrissake!
- 冰人有麻煩 - 笨鵝，和我說說話
- Ice is in trouble! - Talk to me, Goose.
快回去，獨行俠 不能把他一個人留下
Get in there, Maverick! He won't last down there alone!
回去戰鬥，為了上帝
Get in the fight, for chrissakes!
獨行俠
Maverick! Maverick!
獨行俠重返戰場了
Maverick's reengaging, sir.
我無法擺脫他
I can't get him off my tail!
冰人，跟著你的米格戰機在我正前方
Ice, I've got your MiG dead ahead. I've got him dead ahead.
位置不錯，鎖定了
Good tone. I've got good tone.
鎖定了，發射
I've got tone! I've got tone! Firing!
- 他們在哪兒？ - 155英里外
- Where? Where are they? - A hundred and fifty-five miles.
兩架米格戰機在正前方 以時速八百英里接近
Two MiGs, dead ahead. Closing at 800 miles an hour.
我看到了，我要引一架去左邊
I see them. I see them. I'm gonna take them down the left side.
天啊
Oh, my God.
冰人在我們下面 他後面有一架米格戰機
Ice is right below us. He's got a MiG on his tail.
他開火了，左轉
He's firing! Break left! Break left!
射過頭了
He overshot! He overshot!
冰人，我來了
Coming in, Ice. I'm coming in.
前面有兩架米格戰機
I got two MiGs dead ahead.
我看到了 一架從我們倆中間飛過
I got him, Mav. One MiG passing between us.
有一架米格戰機在你左邊，在三點鐘方向
You got a MiG on your left. On your left! 3 o'clock!
他要開火了
He's gonna fire, he's gonna fire!
獨行俠，小心北面的米格戰機
Maverick, check the guys to the north! Check the guys to the north!
左轉
Banking left. Banking left.
他在那兒，冰人，消滅他
There he is. Get him, Ice. Get him!
好，我來了
Okay, you guys, I'm coming in!
獨行俠，有一架米格戰機正飛向我們後面
Maverick, we got a MiG coming around on our tail!
- 我們要離開這 - 我不能離冰人而去
- We gotta get out of here! - I can't leave Ice.
他仍然在轉向 他要到我們後面了
He's still coming around! He's gonna get behind us!
我不會離僚機而去
I'm not leaving my wingman.
我在他後面，我來對付他
I'm on his tail. I'm on his tail. I'm going for it.
我來對付他，我要向他開火
I'm going for it. I'm going for the shot right now.
收到，準備
Roger. Engaged.
雷達已經鎖定了
I've got radar lock.
位置不錯，我要開火了
Good tone. I'm taking a shot.
發射
Fire!
- 好棒！ - 消滅那個笨蛋了
- Bingo! - Wash that sucker, yeah!
冰人，小心 你右邊有一架米格戰機，他開火了
Ice, watch out. There's a MiG to your right. He's firing!
我被擊中了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
我們的右引擎被擊中
We're hit in the right engine!
我正在把它關掉
I'm shutting it down. I'm shutting it down.
冰人，快逃
Coming in, Ice. Coming in.
冰人，敵機仍然在你後面 我準備開火
Ice, that bogey's still behind you. I'm maneuvering for a shot.
別放過他，獨行俠
Stay with him, Mav, stay with him!
- 快開火，擊落他 - 冰人，我無法鎖定目標
- Take the shot! Nail him! Nail him! - Shit. Ice, I can't get a tone.
快開火，獨行俠 我無法擺脫他
Shoot, Maverick! I can't get him off my tail!
- 獨行俠，我們又被擊中了 - 不要緊
- Maverick, we're hit! We're hit again! - It's okay.
引擎仍然能運作，我們沒事
Both engines are functioning. We're okay.
冰人，我數三聲後向右轉
Ice, on the count of three, break hard right!
三、二、一，向右突圍
Three, two, one. Break right!
開火
Firing!
該死，打不中
Damn it, I missed!
別放過他，繼續攻擊他
Don't let him go. Keep on him, Mav. Keep on him.
我看到他了
I got him. I got him.
再來一記
Here comes a shot.
全取三分！
Scratch three!
獨行俠，快避開 後面有米格戰機
Maverick, move! There's a MiG on your tail! There's a MiG on your tail!
我們有麻煩了，只剩下一顆導彈
We've got a problem here. We've only got one missile left.
- 以時速110英里接近，長官 - 該死的
- Approaching 110 miles, sir. - Goddamn it.
我看到他了，他就在我們後面
I got him! I got him! He's right on us! He's between our tails!
該死
Shit.
還沒甩掉他，他仍然跟著我們
You haven't lost him. He's still with us!
你在做什麼？你竟然減速？
What are you doing? You're slowing down! You're slowing down!
- 我要引他飛近一點 - 什麼？
- I'm bringing him in closer, Merlin. - You're gonna do what?
獨行俠，是時候了
This is it, Maverick!
我要拉制動器，讓他飛過頭
I'm gonna hit the brakes, he'll fly right by.
該死，他會鎖定我們的
Shit! He's gonna get a lock on us!
就是現在
Now!
鎖定了，發射
I got a good lock. Firing.
幹掉4架！
Scratch four!
母艦，我是伏都三號 剩下的米格戰機都撤離了
Mustang, this is Voodoo three. Remaining MiGs are bugging out.
母艦，我是獨行俠，請求低空飛越
Mustang, this is Maverick requesting flyby.
不批准，鬼怪騎士，都滿了
Negative, Ghost Rider. The pattern is full.
對不起，有什麼事該讓我知道嗎？
Excuse me. Something I should know about?
謝謝
Thank you.
臭小子
Goddamn that guy.
皮特·米切爾－獨行俠
你
You!
你仍然很危險
You are still dangerous.
不過你隨時可以做我的僚機
You can be my wingman anytime.
屁話，你做我的
Bullshit. You can be mine.
- 獨行俠 - 長官
- Maverick. - Sir.
成為所有英文報紙的頭條 有什麼感覺？
How does it feel to be on the front page of every newspaper in the English-speaking world?
雖然另一方否認這件事
Even though the other side denies the incident,
- 恭喜你 - 謝謝
- congratulations. - Thank you, sir.
他們讓你選擇你的職位
They gave you your choice of duty, son.
任何職位，任何地方 你能相信嗎？
Anything, anywhere. Do you believe that shit?
你想去哪兒？
Where do you think you wanna go?
我想當教官
I thought of being an instructor, sir.
- 到高空利劍？ - 是，長官
- Top Gun? - Yes, sir.
願主保佑我們
God help us.
皮特·米切爾，你好
Hello, Pete Mitchell.
聽說精英中的精英回來了 所以…
I heard the best of the best were gonna be back here, so...
這會變得很複雜
This could be complicated.
第一次是一次大災難
You know, on the first one, I crashed and burned.
第二次呢？
And the second?
我不知道，不過…
I don't know, but...
暫時看來還不錯
...it's looking good so far.